Inventory of the W. H. (William Harold) Hutt Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
W. H. (William Harold) Hutt Papers
1925-1989
89017
Hutt, W. H. (William Harold), 1899-
85 manuscript boxes (33.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Contains speeches and writings, correspondence, pamphlets, serial issues, and other printed matter, relating to laissez-faire economic theory, and to economic conditions and race relations in South Africa by Hutt, a South African economist.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1899 August 3 Born, London
1917-1919 Served, Royal Air Force
1924 B. Com., London
1924-1926 Manager, Individualist Bookshop, Ltd.
1927-1965 Senior lecturer and professor, University of Cape Town, Republic of South Africa
1930 Author, The Theory of Collective Bargaining (2nd edition, 1975)
1931-1964 Professor and dean, Faculty of Commerce, University of Cape Town
1931 Served on the Executive Committee of Senate, University of Cape Town
1936 Author, Economics and the Public
1938 Elected honorary president, National Union of South African Students
1939 Author, The Theory of Idle Resources (2nd edition, 1977)
1943 Author, Plan for Reconstruction
1947 Founding member of Mont Pelerin Society
circa 1950 Elected to a University Fellowship in recognition of outstanding scholarship
1963 Author, Keynesianism--Retrospect and Prospect
1964 Author, The Economics of the Colour Bar
1965 Professor emeritus (retired)
1966 Visiting professor, University of Virginia, Author, Neo-Keynesianism and Academic Freedom
1966-1981 Visiting professor of economics, University of Virginia, followed by appointments in other universities and colleges throughout the United States
1969-1971 Research fellow, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, California
1970-1971 Distinguished visiting professor of economics, California state colleges
1971 Author, Politically Impossible?
1971-1977 Distinguished professor, economics, University of Dallas, Texas
1973 Author, The Strike-Threat System
1975 Author, A Rehabilitation of Say's Law
1976 Author, Individual Freedom: A Symposium of Articles, 1934-1975, selected and edited by David Klingaman and Pejivich
1977 Awarded degree of Doctor of Laws (LLD) honoris causas, University of Cape Town
1979 Awarded degree of Doctor of Social Science honoris causas, Universidad Francisco Marroquin, Guatemala City. Author, The Keynesian Episode
1984 Awarded honorary degree of Doctor of Human Letters, University of Dallas. Named a Roe senior fellow of the Mont Pelerin Society
1987 Adjunct scholar, Ludwig von Mises Institute, Auburn, Alabama
1988 June 19 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 1990, followed by an increment in 1994, the William Harold Hutt papers consist of speeches and writings, correspondence, pamphlets, serial issues, and other printed matter, relating to laissez-faire economic theory, and to economic conditions and race relations in South Africa.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Laissez-faire.; Economics.; Liberty.; South Africa--Economic conditions.; South Africa--Race relations.
Occupations
Economists.
Container List
- Addresses by James Stockdale about his experiences as a Vietnam prisoner-of-war, undated, and by Br. Suviranta on indemnity payments after the Second World War, 1959 (Box 1)
- Articles by others relating to economic history and development in general, 1920-1978.
  Also concerns other issues, such as energy, inflation, balance of payment, national health service, social benefits, trade union policies, urbanization, and related matters affecting Great Britain, South Africa, and the United States
- Papers by Barbara Shenfield and Ljubo Sirc, Mont Pelerin Society conference and meeting, 1971 and undated
- Memoranda, newsletter, and reports, 1972-1977.
  Includes a report on Ludwig Erhard and Mont Pelerin Society
- Ronald Reagan--William Hutt's letters to him, 1980-1983. (Box-folder 2: 1)
  Includes a letter to the editor by William Hutt and photocopies of articles by Geoffrey Wood
- Collected articles. Arranged by first letter of author's surname
  - W
    - 1948-1964 (Folder 2: 2)
    - 1949-1976 (Folder 2: 3)
- Articles and book reviews, 1975-1983. (Box 2)
  Includes a draft by William Hutt on Keynesian debate and a cover letter to Edwin J. Feulner, Jr., 1983
- Cato Clippings, 1982
- Center for the Study of Public Choice, 1981.
  Annual report
- Foundation Francisco Marroquin, 1982.
  Annual report and prospectus
- Heritage Foundation, 1982.
  Collection of essays
- Remarks, undated.
  "Twenty Five Years of Socialism in India: An Assessment," William Hutt
- Report, undated, by William H. Hutt on prize essay competition organized by the Cato Institute
- World Research Institute, 1980-1982.
  Annual report and Education Materials Catalog
- Journals and bulletin, 1975-1982; newsletters, 1978-1982; and miscellany, undated
- American-Chilean Council, 1978. (Box-folder 3: 1)
  Form letter, letter from William A. Rusher to John Davis Lodge, and reports
- National Right to Work Committee Educational Services, 1978-1983 (Box 3)
  - General information, 1979.
    Includes agenda, list of attendees for the annual meeting, map, memoranda, newsletters, press release, and program
  - Clipping and schedule of events, 1983
  - Miscellany, 1978-1979
- Concerned Educators against Forced Unionism
  - Articles, fact sheet, form letter, press release, program, and schedule, 1980-1983
    - Seminar, 1983.
      Miscellany
- American Banker, 1977
- Ohio University Press/Swallow Press, 1983
  Includes schedule, 1981-1982
- Laissez Faire Books, Inc., 1983.
  Catalog and newsletter
- Orientacion Economica, 1972
- Publications catalogues, 1977-1984
- Bulletin, press release, and miscellany, 1979-1982
- Newspaper clippings and photocopies, 1966-1983. (Box-folder 4: 1)
  Includes articles by William Hutt
- Concerned Educators against Forced Unionism, 1980. (Box 4)
- National Association of Manufacturers, 1979.
- Articles, brochure, catalogues, journal, memoranda, newsletters, report, and miscellany relating to various economic issues, 1971-1983
- Law and Liberty, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- Lefevre's Journal, 1974-1975 (Folder 5: 2)
- Robert LeFevre, 1966-1967. (Folder 5: 3)
  Correspondence with William Hutt and others
- Libertarian organizations, 1977-1980. (Folder 5: 4)
  Announcement of the libertarian movement's first magazine of events, clipping, letters, memorandum, and newsletter
- Mont Pelerin Society, 1956-1977. (Folder 5: 5)
  Includes agenda for meeting, historical background, lists of guests and members attending the special European meeting, membership directory, newsletter, program, and statement of aims and by-laws
- National Association of Manufacturers, 1976-1979. (Folder 5: 6)
  Journal, newsletter, and report
- National Dividend Plan (NDP), 1977. (Folder 5: 7)
  Newsletters
- Pacific Legal Foundation--The Reporter, 1977. (Folder 5: 8)
  Newsletter
- L. T. Patterson Strategy Letter, 1977-1978. (Folder 5: 9)
- Perkins' Economics, 1978. (Folder 5: 10)
- Republican organizations, 1978. (Folder 5: 11)
  Grand Old Party campaign victory plan and related material
- Rockford College Institution, 1977-1978. (Folder 5: 12)
  Brochure and newsletter
- Royal Bank of Canada, 1976-1978. (Folder 5: 13)
- Americans against Union Control of Government, 1977-1979. (Folder 5: 14)
  Annual report, letters, and newsletters
- American Enterprise Institute, 1977-1979. (Folder 5: 15)
- Committee for Monetary Research and Education, Inc. sixth annual conference, 1977-1978. (Folder 5: 16)
  Biographical information, list of guests, program, and remarks
- United States Congress, 1977-1979. (Folder 5: 17)
  Form letters including some to William Hutt and list of members of the Senate. Includes 1 photographic print depicting president Gerald Ford and James Baker with a message from the president written on the other side and signed by him, undated
- Sir Leonard Neal, 1975. (Folder 5: 18)
  Preface-- The Theory of Collective Bargaining by William Hutt
- Sylvester Petro, 1977 and undated. (Folder 5: 19)
  Report on the social and legal research projects submitted under his leadership by the Institute for Labor Policy Analysis, Wake Valley University, North Carolina. Includes a letter to William Hutt [?]
- Rehabilitation of Say's Law, 1974-1975. (Folder 5: 20)
  Comments on draft copy, letters, list of individuals to whom copies were sent, names and addresses of others, and preface
- Rules for teachers, 1872. (Folder 5: 21)
  Photocopy of a list
- Material, 1974-1978 (Box 5)
  Letter from G. Anders to William Hutt, newsletters, and schedule for Mont Pelerin Society meeting, Brussels, and PHM Credit Corporation prospectus, 1974-1978
- William Hutt--Reviews and replies about other people, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Economics of the Colour Bar, 1966. (Folder 6: 2)
  Correspondence and review
- The Keynesian Episode, 1980. (Folder 6: 3)
  Correspondence and reviews
- Keynesianism--Retrospect and Prospect, 1963-1964. (Folder 6: 4)
  Reviews
- Plan for Reconstruction, 1943-1945. (Folder 6: 5)
- William Hutt
  - Reviews by others, 1971-1978 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Miscellaneous articles about him, 1931-1967 (Folder 6: 7)
- Theory of Collective Bargaining, 1960-1963. (Folder 6: 8)
- Dean Witter, 1978. (Folder 6: 9)
- William Hutt, 1975-1978. (Folder 6: 10)
  Curriculum vitae, list of academic conferences attended, selected contributions to articles and books, and publications
- Economic Problem, 1977-1979. (Folder 6: 11)
- Forecast, 1978-1979. (Folder 6: 12)
- Foundation for Research and Education, undated. (Folder 6: 13)
  Form letter and related materials seeking financial contributions
- Fraser Institute, 1976-1978. (Folder 6: 14)
  Newsletter, Fraser Currents, and press release
- Billy James Hargis' Christian Crusade Weekly, form letter, and opinion survey data card, 1978 (Folder 6: 15)
- Imprints, Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Michigan, 1976-1978. (Folder 6: 16)
  Includes Independence, newsletter of Hillsdale Freedom Fund, and a form letter from George Roche
- Die Individualis (The Individualist), 1976-1977. (Folder 6: 17)
- Informacion Económica, 1978. (Folder 6: 18)
- Institute for Contemporary Studies--The Letter, 1976-1979. (Folder 6: 19)
  Includes form letter and newsletter
- The Institute for Humane Studies, 1978. (Folder 6: 20)
  Form letters and newsletter, Inform
- Intercollegiate Studies Institute Campus Report, 1977-1978 and undated. (Folder 6: 21)
  Includes a program, "The Role of Business in Society," summary report, and fund proposal, 1977-1978
- International Biographical Centre Magazine, 1977-1978. (Folder 6: 22)
- Lord Keynes, 1956-1971. (Folder 6: 23)
  Includes articles by him and correspondence with A. W. Philips, T. W. Price, Barry L. Prince, and Austin Robinson
- Irving Kristol, 1975. (Folder 6: 24)
  Articles
- "Comments on Lachmann's Paper," William Hutt, undated (Folder 6: 25)
- Commission of Inquiry into the Monetary System and Monetary Policy in South Africa, 1977-1978. (Box-folder 7: 1)
  Letter from Gerhard P. C. de Kock to William Hutt, questionnaire, and description of the task of the commission
- Federal Trade Commission, 1979. (Folder 7: 2)
  Fragment of a letter to Mr. and Mrs. Hutt
- Economics courses and examinations by class, 1971-1976 (Folder 7: 3)
- Gottfried Haberler, 1964-1965. (Folder 7: 4)
  Correspondence with William Hutt
- Friederich A. V. Hayek
  - Correspondence with William Hutt and letters from Fritz Machlup and Kenneth S. Templeton, Jr., 1961-1965 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Address, announcement of a meeting of the Mont Pelerin Society devoted to the work of F. A. Hayek, articles by and about him, excerpts from Fritz Machlup "Friedrich..." interview, and miscellany, 1975 (Folder 7: 6)
- Henry Hazlitt, 1959-1980. (Folder 7: 7)
  Article by him and correspondence with William Hutt. Includes a letter from William Hutt to Henry Regnery
- William Hutt
  - Articles chiefly relating to South Africa, 1976 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1965-1966. (Folder 7: 9)
    Clipping and letters to the editor
  - Newspaper articles and letters, 1971-1976 (Folder 7: 10)
- Miscellany, 1970-1977. (Box 7)
  Clippings, newspaper articles, and speech
- Dead work from autobiography, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Correspondence.
  Includes related materials
  - B, 1979 (Folder 8: 2)
  - C-D, 1955. (Folder 8: 3)
    Includes an article, "The Burden of Debt: A Neo-Classical Analysis"
  - W
    - General, 1973-1983 (Folder 8: 4)
    - World Research, Inc., 1973-1983 (Folder 8: 5)
  - X-Y, 1966-1983. (Folder 8: 6)
    Includes Young Americans for Freedom
  - Z, 1975-1976 (Folder 8: 7)
- Conferences--Miscellaneous, 1977 (Folder 8: 8)
- Newspaper clippings--General, 1968-1979 (Folder 8: 9)
- Miscellaneous articles--Newspaper and periodical, 1963-1967 (Folder 8: 10)
- Miscellany, 1969-1976. (Folder 8: 11)
  Articles, clippings, and remarks
- "The Impoverishers: A Postscript,", 1984. (Box-folder 9: 1-4)
  Alterations, chapters XV and XVII, copies, and early drafts
- Additional copies of the "Impoverishers,", 1984 (Box 9)
- Hugh C. Newton, 1976.
  Article and cover letter
- Brief biographical information of some participants, undated
- International Freedom Academy (INFRA), 1969.
  12th quarterly report
- Private Enterprise Management Workshop, undated.
  Sponsored by Center for Business Services and Texas Association of Business, College of Business Administration, University of Texas, Arlington. Collection of papers
- Tax imitation/Balanced budget agreement, undated.
  Brochure
- Journals on economics, 1966.
  In Japanese
- Writings by William Hutt (Box 10)
  - "Seeds of Change in South Africa,", undated (Folder 10: 1)
  - "Should Moscow Choose Leaders for the United States?", undated (Folder 10: 2)
  - "The Impoverishers: A Postscript,", 1984
    - First draft (Folder 10: 3)
    - Early draft (Folder 10: 4)
    - Final copy (Folder 10: 5)
  - "Conservative Party,", undated (Folder 10: 6)
  - Autobiography, undated (Folder 10: 7)
  - "The Impoverishers: A Postscript,", 1984. (Box 10)
    Typescript original copy
  - "The Free Choice of Gold as Currency,", 1984 [?]
  - "How to End Inflation and Unemployment,", undated
  - "Trade Unions and the Free Market,", undated
  - "A Rehabilitation of Say's Law,", 1973 February.
    Comments
- Miscellany, undated.
  An article and fragment of a letter to the editor of National Review
- Correspondence (Box 11)
  - Old (private) letters
    - University of Cape Town, 1984. (Folder 11: 1)
      Includes announcement of United States alumni gathering
    - Letter from Leonard J. Heller to William Hutt regarding rental determination of William Hutt's house, 1973
  - Letter to Irving Kristol, The Public Interest, 1979, and letter from George [?], Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Michigan, 1981 (Folder 11: 2)
- Article relating to labor relation, strike-threat, and related issues, undated (Folder 11: 3)
- Letter to the Heritage Foundation regarding the appraisal and publication of "An Economist for the Long Run,", 1984. (Folder 11: 4)
- Article about William Hutt, papers by others, and reviews by students, 1973-1981 (Folder 11: 5)
- "The Impoverishers: A Postscript," by William Hutt, undated. (Folder 11: 6)
  Chapters I-III
- Autobiography, 1984. (Folder 11: 7)
  Copy 2
- Materials, 1946-1988. (Box 11)
  Includes articles and reviews by William Hutt and about him, piece by Glen Campbell, comments, letters, letters to the editor, letter concerning Hutt's nomination for the Nobel Prize, list of Hutt's writings, newsletter, notes, and related materials
- Correspondence (Box 12)
  - General--Letters, 1982-1987 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Letters arranged by first letter of author's surname
    - D, 1975-1983 (Folder 12: 2-3)
    - D-F, 1940-1981 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Dallas Morning News, 1974-1982. (Folder 12: 5)
    Correspondence
- Writings by William Hutt
  - "Keynes and Monetary Nationalism,", undated (Folder 12: 6)
  - Idle Resources, undated. (Folder 12: 7-8)
    Draft chapters [?]
  - Discarded, redundant, and ancient, undated (Folder 12: 9-10)
  - "Money, Public Good or Private Good,", undated (Folder 12: 11)
- "Insurance," undated, and drafts of "The Impoverishers--A Postscript," chapter 3/conclusion (Box 12)
- Correspondence. (Box 13)
  - General
    - B, 1959-1983. (Folder 13: 1)
      Includes 2 photographic prints depicting Eric Brodin, 1982
    - Ca-Com, 1963-1983 (Folder 13: 2)
    - Con-Cz, 1970-1981 (Folder 13: 3)
    - D, 1977-1980 (Folder 13: 4-5)
    - E, 1969-1983 (Folder 13: 6)
    - F, 1963-1983 and; 1971-1982 (Folder 13: 7)
    - A, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Record, 1972 April - 1977 (Folder 14: 2)
  - Photocopies of important letters
    - 1973-1976 (Folder 14: 3)
    - 1977-1979 (Folder 14: 4-6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1940-1967 (Folder 14: 7)
- Notes, undated (Folder 14: 8)
- Class notes, reading list, and lectures [?], undated (Folder 14: 9)
- Mont Pelerin Society--Paper responses, 1968 (Folder 14: 10)
- Miscellany, 1957-1987. (Folder 14: 11)
  Letters and drafts of writings
- Correspondence (Box 15)
  - A-C, 1927-1980 (Folder 15: 1)
  - Out, 1987 September - 1988 March (Folder 15: 2)
  - Managerial and Decision Economics (MDE), 1986-1987. (Folder 15: 3)
    For special issue
- Writings by William Hutt.
  - "History of Economic Thought: The Austrian School,", undated (Folder 15: 4-5)
  - "Hutchinson and Adam Smith" and "Division of Labor,", undated (Folder 15: 6)
  - "Economic Institutions and the New Socialism,", 1940 (Folder 15: 7)
  - "Immigration under Economic Freedom,", 1970 (Folder 15: 8)
  - "The Economic Position of the Bantu in South Africa,", 1967 (Folder 15: 9)
  - "Reaganomics and 'Say's Law',", undated (Folder 15: 10)
  - "The Impoverishers: A Postscript,", 1984 (Folder 15: 11)
  - "The Nature of Coordination through the Price System,", undated. (Folder 15: 12)
    Includes a list of selected contributions
  - "Economics of the Colour Bar,", 1986. (Folder 15: 13-14)
    Typescript drafts
  - "The Power of Union Rulers,", 1968 [?]. (Folder 15: 15)
    Includes notes on some fundamental concepts for lectures in Economics 203
  - "The Economics and Prospects of Apartheid in the Republic of South Africa--The Economics of the Colour Bar,", undated (Folder 15: 16)
  - "Trade Unions and the Free Market,", undated. (Folder 15: 17)
    Second half new as of 1986 October 17
  - "The Power of Labor Unions," part I, undated. (Folder 15: 18)
    Working copy
  - "A Suggested Fundamental Economic Law,", 1986 (Folder 15: 19)
  - "Shared Entrepreneurship,", 1981 (Folder 15: 20)
  - "The Effects of Immigration on Earnings,", 1930 (Folder 15: 21)
  - Reviews of Keynesianism--Retrospect and Prospect, 1963 (Folder 15: 22)
- Articles—Index, 1978 (Folder 15: 23)
- "Some Austrian Perspectives on Keynesian Fiscal Policy and the Recovery in the Thirties," by Gene Smiley, 1985. (Folder 15: 24)
  Includes a letter from Walter E. Grinder to Michael Dixon
- Miscellany, 1985. (Folder 15: 25)
  Articles, clippings, conference papers, letters, list of participants, remarks by Lewis Lehrman, schedule, speeches by Alan Greenspan, and statement by Bernardo Grinspun
- "Cosine Plagues,", 1938-1948. (Box-folder 16: 1)
  Articles, clippings, letters, minutes of meeting, outline of an agreement, report, and telegram
- Tyres and motor trades, 1938-1942. (Folder 16: 2)
  Announcement, article by William Hutt titled "Motor Trades and the Public," clippings, letters, list of students in engineering economics final year, notes, and reports
- Economic Society of South Africa (Cape Town branch), 1926-1933. (Folder 16: 3)
  Central Council minutes, correspondence, and notices
- Old reviews, 1963-1974. (Folder 16: 4)
  Includes articles, clippings, letter, newsletter, note, and press release
- Notes on property rights, undated (Folder 16: 5)
- Old correspondence and miscellany, 1964-1984 (Folder 16: 6)
- Oswald St. Clair, 1955-1958. (Folder 16: 7)
  Citation for the award of the honorary degree of D.Litt., clippings, letters, memoranda, report, reviews by him, and telegram
- Material, 1955-1977. (Box 16)
  Includes address; article, "Memorandum on the Dollar Price of Gold" by William Hutt; letters; and writings by others
- Miscellaneous articles, 1984 (Box-folder 17: 1)
- Clippings, 1984-1985 (Folder 17: 2)
- Articles, clippings, and newsletters, 1966-1972 (Folder 17: 3)
- Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Folder 17: 4)
- Free taxes, 1985-1986. (Folder 17: 5)
  Correspondence with M. P. Bhatt, Dan C. Heldman, and Reed Irvine
- Correspondence, 1984 January - December (Folder 17: 6-7)
- Miscellany, 1981-1984. (Folder 17: 8)
  Article, interview, letters, and newsletter
- Correspondence--In, 1987 September - 1988 March (Folder 17: 9)
- Working copies of articles, undated (Folder 17: 10)
- Article--Fragment, undated (Folder 17: 11)
- Unidentified, 1984 (Folder 17: 12)
- "Economics of Private Enterprise" by William Hutt, undated (Folder 17: 13)
- Miscellany, 1957-1989. (Box 17)
  Includes agenda for annual general meeting, London School of Economics Society, articles by William Hutt and others, brochure for William Hutt Memorial Lecture on Economic Policy, clippings, correspondence, faculty appointment agreement between William Hutt and the University of Dallas, newsletters, University of Texas at Arlington information package, and miscellany
- "Non-Keynesian Economics: A Restatement,", undated. (Box-folder 18: 1)
  Draft chapters I-XIX
- Reviews of William Hutt's works, 1944-1976. (Folder 18: 2)
  Includes announcement of annual commencement, University of Dallas, 1984
- Keynes--Chapter I, undated (Folder 18: 3)
- Who's Who--Self, 1983-1984 (Folder 18: 4)
- "Definitions of Idleness," William Hutt, undated (Folder 18: 5)
- "Economic Power and Labor Unions," William Hutt, undated. (Folder 18: 6)
  Summary. Includes related materials
- W. H. Hutt--An economist for this century, undated. (Folder 18: 7)
  Acknowledgement and list of chapters from some of his writings
- Miscellaneous notes and William Hutt's letter to George Koether, 1964 [?] (Folder 18: 8)
- Miscellany, 1971-1976. (Folder 18: 9)
  Articles, clippings, curriculum vitae of Paul Craig Roberts, letters from different individuals to William Hutt chiefly relating to his writings, newsletters, and review of The Strike Threat System: The Economic Consequences of Collective Bargaining by David Williams
- Articles, letters, and newsletter relating to South Africa and the United States, 1969-1976. (Folder 18: 10)
  Includes review of Strike Threat System: The Economic Consequences of Collective Bargaining
- Notes, undated (Folder 18: 11)
- William Hutt on market economy, undated. (Folder 18: 12)
  Article
- Articles, letter to the editor, and notes by William Hutt, 1983-1984 (Folder 18: 13)
- "Wage Injustices in South Africa," William Hutt, undated. (Folder 18: 14)